( wind howling )
( woman speaking in distance )
- [ Man ] Where would we put all that luggage
if we carried the skies ?
( family laughing )
- [ Woman ] You are very strong .
- [ Man ] Push .
- This is the last holiday I 'm ever going on with you .
- Where 'd you get all this muscle ?
- Come on .
- More , more , more !
Don 't quit now !
- This is terrific .
- How much further ?
- Oh , it 's only a couple million more miles .
- [ Woman ] A couple of what ?
- A couple of million more miles .
Right up here we 're gonna stop .
Keep pushing , don 't quit .
- Mexico next time .
- Hawaii 's better .
- Yeah .
- Whoa .
Hold it . Holt it .
That 's good .
( wind howling )
( sighing )
- Now what 're you gonna do ?
- I 'm gonna try to catch some help .
( sighing )
- Come on , let 's have a snowball fight .
- Oh no ! No !
( laughing )
No !
- Daddy , come on !
Help me , daddy !
( chuckling )
- Yes , do you have the number for emergency road service ?
( motor rumbling )
( laughing )
( tires screeching )
( truck horn honking )
( booming )
( wind howling )
( somber music )
( dramatic piano music )
- Thank you , Stan .
- If you wanna hand with anything ,
just give me a shout , Mr. Russell .
- I will , thanks .
( distant police siren )
( somber piano music )
- Daddy !
Catch !
( giggling )
( ball thudding )
- Mr. Russell .
- Do you know that this piece is going to Seattle too ,
Estancia ?
- [ Estancia ] Yes , sir .
- Good .
( airplane engines whooshing )
( airport commotion )
First , right after it happened , I was in shock .
I just functioned automatically .
I didn 't feel anything .
And one day it hit me .
Joanna and Kathy are gone .
I just kept walking around the apartment ,
saying it over and over and over .
" They 're gone , they 're gone , they 're gone . "
I guess I was about half crazy .
That 's over four months ago ,
what I 've gotta do now is start making demands of myself .
- Your first class is next Monday .
I 've set up a meeting tomorrow with some of the faculty .
You 'll remember a lot of them .
11 okay for you ?
- That 's fine , Robert , thanks .
Thanks for everything you 've done .
- Ah , come on .
Everyone 's very excited about you being here .
- A well known alumnus and distinguished composer
like yourself .
( chuckling )
- Says who ?
- Distinguished or not , we 're glad you came .
- [ Girl ] Give it to me , come on !
Give it to me !
- [ Boy ] No !
- Okay , kids , keep it down .
Go into the kitchen and get yourself some cookies .
Bye the way , how long are you planning to stay in the hotel ?
There 's plenty of room for you here , you know .
- Oh no , thanks .
I think I 'm gonna find a house to rent .
I 've got some things coming out .
What I need is a place I can lock myself in
and pound away at the piano all night .
A place I can work .
- I have a friend who works for
the Historical Preservation Society .
They have some old houses that I 'm sure they rent .
We 'll see what we can come up with for you .
- Good .
( dramatic piano music )
- [ Woman ] Mr. Russell ?
- Yes .
- Hello , I 'm Claire Norman .
Why don 't you hop in and we 'll drive up .
- Fine .
( dramatic music )
( somber music )
When was the house last occupied ?
- Let 's see .
About 12 years ago .
It 's been with the Historical Society
for the past 12 years .
There we go .
( laughing )
- Wow .
- There were plans , at one time ,
to turn it into some kind of a museum .
But I don 't know ,
I guess the house was meant to be lived in .
- Why hasn 't it been lived in ?
- I 've only been with the Society for a year now .
The impression I get is that they haven 't
tried very hard with this place .
Of course , it does need a lot of work .
- Yeah . ( chuckling )
- There 's some pieces here
that are just stored .
You 'd have your pick of them .
You know , whatever you like .
( chuckling )
Kitchen 's in here .
- What does it take to maintain a house of this size ?
- Oh , we have a man who looks after all of these places .
Mr. Tuttle .
And ...
this is the music room .
This is really why I thought of you and this house .
The piano was left here when the society took over .
Just too much trouble to move , really .
Must be in very bad shape .
- What are the terms ?
( somber piano music )
( piano key thumping )
( knocking )
- Sorry to disturb your composing .
- That 's all right , Mr. Tuttle .
This has already been composed .
- There 's a man at the front .
Wants to deliver a water storage tank .
Says you called him .
- Oh , okay .
( piano key ringing )
( ominous music )
- Have you managed to do any writing ?
- Yes , I 'm still working on the second movement .
Same old problem .
Well , maybe the lectures will help get some new ideas going .
( crowd commotion )
( voices hushing )
( clearing throat )
It 's my understanding
that there are 23 students registered ...
( students laughing )
for this series of lectures on Advanced Musical Form .
Now we all know that it 's not raining outside .
( laughing )
unless there 's a fire in some other part of the building
that we don 't know about ...
( laughing )
An awful lot of people here with nothing better to do .
( students laughing )
However ,
we 'll know more after the second lecture .
I 'm sure there are many of you who may recognize this .
( fast piano music )
( exciting orchestra music )
( crowd applauding )
Sounded a little bit better with an orchestra
than it does with a piano .
- Oh no , you made it sound fun .
It was a great class .
- John 's secret is that he 's a natural ham .
- Now you go too far .
Excuse me .
- If you can 't find your way back - -
- Send out a search party .
( crowd commotion )
- Hi .
I 'd like you to meet my mother .
- How do you do , Mrs. Norman ?
- How do you do ?
- This is John Russell .
You remember the Chessman House ?
- Oh , yes , yes .
I 'm very pleased to meet you , Mr. Russell .
How are you liking the place ?
- Fine .
- It 's so large .
( laughing )
- [ Announcer ] Ladies and gentlemen ,
may I have your attention please ?
I 'd like to introduce Senator Joseph Carmichael -
[ Mrs. Norman ] My God .
He 's gonna make another speech .
- [ Claire ] What 're you 're hearing is a lifelong Republican
commenting on the enemy .
- [ John ] I see .
( crowd applauding )
- You know how I hate making speeches .
( crowd laughing )
But sometimes , on a very special occasion ,
like raising money for out magnificent symphony orchestra ,
and weren 't they fantastic tonight ?
( applauding )
Well done .
- I was just going to get a drink .
- I think I 'll join you .
I 'll be right back , mother .
- Thank you .
Actually , he 's on our board of directors
at the Historical Preservation Society .
In fact , he 's become out number one philanthropist .
So , are you getting settled in then ?
- Oh yes .
- Good .
There 's some things at the Society office
that belong to your house .
I 'll see if I can dig them up for you .
I 'm glad you took that house .
( crowd applauding )
( somber music )
( thunder rumbling )
( eerie music )
( unsettling music )
( water dripping )
( refrigerator buzzing )
( deep thudding )
( somber piano music )
( door creaking )
( ominous music )
- Mr. Tuttle ?
Mr. Tuttle ?
( thudding )
- Mr. Russell ?
- You frightened me .
Is anyone else here ?
Mrs. Rissian cleaning today ?
- No , sir . Just me .
- Thank you .
( sighing )
( piano tune playing )
( breath whooshing )
( pleasant piano music )
- That 's lovely .
The music .
- Oh , hello .
- Hi .
Has the quality of a lullaby .
- Yes , it is , in fact .
- Well , here we are , as promised .
These are some assorted prints
that used to hang in the house .
- Ah .
- And this is an old restored photograph
taken in front of the house .
- It 's that remarkable .
( chuckling )
- I tried to call you first
but information isn 't giving your number out yet .
That 's a beautiful old piece .
Did you finish it ?
- I didn 't , no .
( chuckling )
- That was Kathy 's , my daughter .
( somber piano music )
- Well , I guess I better be off .
I hope you like the prints .
- Thank you .
- You going riding ?
- Yes .
Do you ride ?
( pleasant music )
( horses neighing )
John ?
What 's the matter ?
- I was just thinking about my daughter , Kathy .
How much she loved horses .
( truck horn blaring )
- Mommy !
( booming )
( sobbing )
( deep pounding )
( clinking )
- An airlock somewhere .
- It was too loud .
Too rhythmic .
( fire rumbling )
- Well , it 's starting at least .
- Why would it happen two mornings in a row ?
Preciously at six o 'clock .
Why does it go on for about half a minute and stop dead ?
It doesn 't make sense .
- A furnace is like anything else , Mr. Russell .
It 's got habits .
It 's an old house .
It makes noises .
( intense instrumental music )
- Well , that 's very good .
( musicians sighing )
We 're still not together on the offbeats
and darling , you 're retiring a little too much
on the last four bars .
Otherwise , it was splendid .
- [ Woman ] Good night !
( thunder rumbling )
See you tomorrow !
( car horn honking )
( dramatic music )
( moan echoing )
( water trickling )
( person laughing )
( laugh echoing )
( dramatic music )
( water faucet trickling )
( faucet stopping )
( faucet squeaking )
( shower spraying )
( dramatic music )
( water faucet trickling )
( moan echoing )
( water trickling )
( foreboding music )
( woman moaning )
( menacing music )
( somber music )
- What I 'm driving at is ,
has anything like this happened in the house before ?
If so , to whom , when and what do they do about it ?
- Since I 've been with the Society ,
the house has been empty .
John , you 're working very hard .
You 've been through a terrible emotional strain .
Isn 't it possible that you -
[ John ] Hallucinating , is that what you 're gonna say ?
- Excuse me .
- [ Claire ] Minnie ?
- Claire , there 's a call for you , your mother .
Should I tell her you 're busy ?
- I 'll be right there .
Excuse me , John , just for a minute .
( distant car horns honking )
- You know there 's some question about your lease ,
Mr. Russell .
- What do you mean ?
- That house shouldn 't have been rented .
Miss Norman rushed those papers
through our attorney 's office .
She did not use proper channels .
- Why should anyone object ?
- That house is not fit to live in .
No one 's been able to live in it .
It doesn 't want people .
- Then there has been trouble in the house before .
( dramatic music )
( glass shattering )
( somber music )
( eerie music )
( moan echoing )
( somber music )
( eerie music )
( moan echoing )
( wind howling )
( metal clanking )
( ominous music )
( thudding )
( clinking )
( deep rhythmic pounding )
( metal squeaking )
( wind howling )
( thudding )
( door creaking )
( unsettling music )
( eerie music )
( door creaking )
( foreboding music )
( somber music )
( ominous music )
( pleasant music box chiming )
( eerie music )
( pleasant piano music )
- [ John ] Claire , listen , it 's note for note .
Same tempo . Even the same key .
What do you think ?
- I don 't know .
It 's a startling coincidence .
But that melody must 've very popular at one time
or it wouldn 't be on the music box .
- I agree but I swear I never heard it
before I played it and recorded it that day you came over .
No .
There 's something ...
Something that 's happened before here .
I 'm not the first .
- I went over the files very carefully .
All the way back to 1920 .
Nothing out of the ordinary .
- Miss Huxley .
- Minnie 's a highly eccentric old woman but she 'd never - -
- No .
She said the house didn 't want people .
She 's mistaken .
Whatever it is ,
is trying desperately to communicate .
The bangings , the water taps .
Broken windowpanes .
All the glass fell outward .
It had to be done from the inside .
Everything that 's happened
has been designed to get me into that attic room .
- I want to see it .
( thunder rumbling )
( rain trickling )
- Look at that book on the desk there .
- CSB .
January 4th , 1909 .
It 's a little child 's writing .
- 1909 .
Who could 've lived here then ?
That 's where I found the music box , on the mantle .
( distant thundering )
Look at the wheelchair .
- Oh my God .
It 's so small .
What was this room ?
( eerie music )
( breath whooshing )
- Former residents , William Sarah Chino and family .
Architect .
Bought the place in 1965 , sold it in 1967 .
Purchased by the Society of Historical Preservation ,
November 1967 through a generous grant
from the Carmichael Foundation .
That 's the senator ?
- Yes .
- Great philanthropist .
- Now where is the rest of this file ?
- Previous occupants .
No previous occupants listed .
- There 's nothing here before 1920 .
Minnie , we 're looking for the Chessman House file , pre 1920 .
Do you know where it is ?
- What is it you want to know ?
- Trying to find out who lived in the house in 1909 .
- A man named Barnard , a doctor .
- Did he have any children , do you know ?
- I believe a son and a daughter .
There was some kind of family tragedy , I think .
He sold the house in 1909 .
- 1909 ?
I 'll set it up for .
- Thank you .
That was fast .
- It 's all ready to go .
Scanners on the right .
- Thank you so much .
Let 's have a look here .
February 9th , these are want ads .
Financial page .
Real estate , more want ads .
- Wait , wait , wait .
- " Cora Barnard , seven year old daughter of
" Doctor Walter Barnard , prominent Seattle physician
" was struck and seriously injured when she ran
" in front of a passing coal cart
" outside her Chessman Park home yesterday .
" She was hastened to St. Margaret 's Hospital
" where her condition remains grave . "
So forth and so on .
- Cora Barnard .
CSB .
( ominous music )
There .
- " Cora S. Barnard .
" Daughter of ...
" Succumbed ...
" In St. Margaret 's Hospital .
" Injuries sustained in a February 15th accident .
" She in mourned by her parents .
" Miss Barnard will be entered in the family plot
" in Brookfield Cemetery . "
( somber music )
- There 's the doctor ...
And his wife .
There 's the brother , Lloyd .
( somber music )
- His little girl , Cora ,
was killed in the street .
It was an accident , almost the same as Kathy .
What is it in that house , Claire ?
What is it doing ? Why is it trying to reach me ?
- John .
- Is it because of my daughter ?
I can 't go through all of this again .
- John , you must get out of that house .
( thumping )
( clock ticking )
( ominous music )
( dramatic music )
( ghostly giggling )
( thumping )
( menacing music )
- I believe everything you 're saying , Mr. Russell .
The noises , the lights , the teleportation of objects .
It 's all very familiar .
Fascinating stuff .
- But the point is ,
what do I do now ?
- Oh !
I tell you what ,
off the record .
We have coming here many mediums and spiritualists and so .
And we test them .
Now , 99 percent
utter frauds .
But the one percent ,
astonishing .
- A medium .
( ominous music )
( knocking )
- Mr. Russell ?
- Yes .
- How do you do ?
My wife , Leah .
- Come in , please .
- Thank you .
- It 's just to your left .
- Could we have these lights off , please ?
( ominous music )
- I thought I would record what happens .
Is that all right ?
- Oh yes , of course .
That 's fine .
Mr. Russell , would you sit there , please ?
- Yes , of course .
- And I 'll sit here .
Thank you .
( eerie music )
( door creaking )
( eerie breathing )
- You 've suffered a cruel loss , John Russell .
You 've lost a wife and child .
The presence in this house is reaching out to you
through that love .
The presence is very strong here .
( ominous music )
It is the child 's presence .
A child who is not at peace .
( door creaking )
Who can not rest .
( ominous music )
The presence is with us .
We sense that you are with us .
Will you talk to us ?
Will you communicate with us ?
Will you come through to us ?
( pencil scribbling )
Will you speak to us ?
( ominous music )
We are here to help you .
What is your name ?
Will you speak to us ?
- Yes .
- What is your name ?
Are you the child , Cora ?
Are you the child killed by the coal cart ?
- [ Albert ] No .
- [ Leah ] What is your name ?
( ominous music )
- Joseph .
- Did you die in this house , Joseph ?
How did you die ?
Is there someone here you wish to communicate with ?
- John .
Help .
John !
Help !
( eerie music )
Mr. Russell , will you sit over here now , please ?
- Will you speak to John ?
Will you tell us why you are not at rest ?
( eerie moaning )
Speak to John .
John is with us .
( eerie music )
What do you want of John ?
Why do you feel no peace ?
( thudding )
Why do you remain in this house , Joseph ?
What is in this house ?
Speak to John .
John is with us .
How did you die ?
Did you die in this house ?
Why do you remain in this house ?
How did you die ?
Joseph , did you die in this house ?
( yelling )
( glass shattering )
( Claire crying )
( foreboding music )
( recorder playback squeaking )
- [ Leah 's Recording ] We are here to help you .
What is your name ?
( recorder rewind buzzing )
Killed by the coal cart ?
- [ Ghostly Whisper ] No .
- [ Albert Recording ] No .
( recorder rewind buzzing )
- [ Leah Recording ] Are you the child killed
by the coal cart ?
- [ Ghost Whisper ] No .
- [ Albert Recording ] No .
( ominous music )
( recorder rewind buzzing )
- [ Leah Recording ] Are you the child killed
by the coal cart ?
- [ Ghost Whisper ] No .
- [ Albert Recording ] No .
- [ Leah Recording ] We are here to help you .
What is your name ?
- [ Ghost Whisper ] Joseph .
- [ Leah Recording ] What is your name ?
( ominous music )
- [ Ghost Whisper ] Joseph .
Joseph .
- [ Albert Recording ] Joseph .
- [ Leah Recording ] Did you die in this house , Joseph ?
- [ Joseph Whisper ] House .
My room .
Can 't walk .
( eerie music )
- [ Leah Recording ] Will you tell us why you are not at rest ?
- [ Joseph Recording ] My father .
- [ Leah Recording ] Joseph , did you die in this house ?
- [ Joseph Recording ] My room .
- [ Leah Recording ] How did you die ?
How did you die ?
- How did you die ?
- [ Joseph ] Father .
Father .
The well .
Ranch .
Took the dark .
My medal .
Father .
Father , don 't .
Help .
( water splashing )
( menacing music )
( boy gagging )
( water splashing )
( deep banging )
( eerie music box chiming )
Body wet .
The well .
My name ,
Joseph Carmichael .
( tape clicking )
( clock ticking )
- Claire ?
Yeah .
I 'm sorry ...
I just ...
Can you ...
( thudding )
- [ Joseph Whisper ] House .
My room .
Can 't walk .
- [ Leah Recording ] Will you tell us why you are not at rest ?
- [ Joseph Recording ] My father .
- [ Leah Recording ] Joseph , did you die in this house ?
- [ Joseph Recording ] My room .
- [ Leah Recording ] How did you die ?
- [ Joseph Recording ] Father , don 't .
My name ,
Joseph Carmichael .
( sobbing )
- Sorry .
I shouldn 't have called you .
It 's just that I needed someone .
( sobbing )
I wrote some words on a paper .
I wrote " sacred heart . "
- It used to be a county orphanage named Sacred Heart .
It was closed down years ago .
- What happened ?
The child , Joseph Carmichael ,
he was murdered in his house , in the attic ,
and buried
and than an orphan .
- Stop it !
For one one minute , please !
( gasping )
( ominous music )
( creaking )
( menacing music )
( suspenseful music )
- Miss Huxley 's on the phone , Senator .
It 's the third time she 's called this morning .
She says it 's important .
- All right , I 'll take it .
- Hello , Minnie , how are you ?
- I 'm fine .
They 've been going through the files .
- Let me have that name again .
John ...
Russell .
- I 'm very glad to be of help , as you know .
Goodbye .
( ominous music )
( city commotion )
- Senator 's campaign bio , 1960 .
I got it from the main library .
Had them xerox it for me .
You found something ?
- It 's some kind of a rough retrospective
that somebody drew up when they were thinking
about turning the house into a museum .
- " Richard Carmichael and family occupied the house
" 1899 to 1960 . "
Richard was the senator 's father .
His mother died when he was born in 1900 .
It 's all in there .
Look at the part about his illness .
- " Joe Carmichael , son at age three ,
" was struck down with a form of arthritis . "
- Further down .
- " Who has decided to send little Joe
" to the famed Northern Sanatorium in Switzerland
" for special therapy .
" Accompanied by his father ,
" he embarked for Europe in October 1906
" and not to set foot on American soil again
" until the succession of World War I. "
- See how it might have been done .
Richard 's son , a sick child ,
was murdered by his father and buried secretly
and a substitute , a six year old orphan ,
was put in his place , shipped right over seas right away ,
with the father attending , it all worked for him .
Even the war worked .
He kept him in Switzerland until 1918 .
He came back here , he was 18 years old ,
who was gonna know that he wasn 't the real son ?
If he wasn 't crippled anymore it was because he was cured .
- John ,
do you think he knows about the murder ?
About the replacement ?
- I don 't know .
- How could any father do such a thing ?
- Richard 's wife was Emily Spencer .
She was the daughter of H.T. Spencer .
Founded the Spencer / Carmichael empire .
He died in 1905 .
He was a zillionaire .
His will might be very interesting .
Must be a copy of it in the hall of records .
I 'm also gonna try to find out if there was a ranch ,
a Spencer or Carmichael ranch somewhere .
Yeah , ranch with a well .
- This is the 1908 atlas of Seattle ,
which is open to the part of the city
where the Carmichael Ranch was located , right here .
- What does that little mark , right there , mean ?
- According to the legend , here ,
that was the location of a well on that property .
- I see .
- But in the 1914 atlas ,
which is opened here to the same area ,
there 's been one large lot that has been apparently sold off
but the property is very much the same
and the location of the well is still given .
- Right .
- In the 1928 atlas ,
there 's quite a change .
There 's further subdivision of the property .
The symbol for the well has disappeared
and a house has been built here .
( water sloshing )
( boat horn blowing )
( seagulls squawking )
( knocking )
( dramatic music )
( suspenseful music )
- The ranch is listed in the will .
Part of the inheritance of little Joseph Carmichael .
All of five years old at the time .
He got just about everything .
- What about the father , Richard ?
- Bypassed .
Except as his son 's guardian ,
and , therefor , a trustee of the estate .
- [ Claire ] Well , old man Spencer 's daughter was dead
and obviously he wasn 't too fond of his son-in-law .
- Yes , but wait .
Richard doesn 't get any money
but he still controls his son
and his son is worth a fortune .
Unless , for some reason ,
the boy dies before obtaining the age of 21 .
In that case , the entire estate goes to charity .
That would have shut Richard out completely .
There he was with a son who was weak , sickly , bedridden .
Couldn 't even walk .
He must 've decided not to take a chance on the boy .
The money was just too tempting .
( dramatic music )
- [ Claire ] What 're you gonna tell her ?
- [ John ] About the well , the house and the body .
- And the medal with the name on it ?
- No , nothing about Carmichael .
- She 'll think you 're crazy .
- You 'll tell her I 'm not .
( laughing )
( knocking )
Good evening Mrs. Grey , I 'm John Russell .
This is Miss Norman .
( water sloshing )
- Mr. Russell ,
I wouldn 't have listened to your story for two minutes ,
I wouldn 't have let you in here ,
bu there 's something you said on the phone earlier .
You said that this seance affair of yours
happened three nights ago , right ?
- That 's right .
- Well , three nights ago ,
on Monday night ,
Linda , my daughter ,
woke up screaming just after midnight .
She had a nightmare .
When I went into her , she was hysterical .
She was sobbing .
I had never seen her like that before .
She had nightmares before .
( distant boat horn blowing )
She said she 'd seen a boy .
A very small , very thin ,
almost gnome-like .
He was trying to come up through the floor .
And he kept staring at her .
Here , in the middle .
She hasn 't been in this room since .
Won 't come near it .
Sleeps with me .
- What we want is ...
- What you want , Mr. Russell ,
is to tear this room apart .
Well , I have your phone number , Mr. Russell .
I 'll have to think about it .
( eerie music )
( wind howling )
( water sloshing )
( ominous music )
( eerie music )
( floor cracking )
( wood bursting )
( screaming )
( ghostly moaning )
( Mrs. Grey yelling )
( saw buzzing )
( boat horn tooting )
( water sloshing )
- They 're still digging .
But they found the well .
- Okay .
Find anything ?
- No , nothing yet .
This is Tony , Mrs. Grey 's son .
- Hi .
( water dripping )
- Give me a flashlight , will you ?
- Sure .
- I think I found something .
- What is it ?
- It 's a hand .
- What ?
- I 'll call the police .
( police radio commotion )
Nothing more ?
- Doesn 't look like it .
- Do you think there might be something else down there ?
- No .
- Assistant coroner said those bones had been down there
maybe 50 years .
Do you have some idea who that child was ?
- No , not really .
- What 's " not really " mean ?
- No .
- I 'm gonna want statements from everybody .
Mrs. Grey , do you have some other place
you could stay for tonight ?
- Yes , it 's all been arranged .
- Good .
( police radio commotion )
- I think you should 've told them .
- It 's gotta be there .
Without that medal , there 's no evidence , there 's nothing .
- You have the tape .
- Tapes can be altered .
They know that .
Did you see the expression on his face ?
- It was obvious you were holding something back .
- I 'll say .
- Look , it 's very late .
Why don 't you get some rest
and I 'll talk to you in the morning .
- Fine , drive careful .
- You too .
( ominous music )
( water dripping )
( glass shattering )
( wind howling )
( ominous music )
( eerie music )
( slow suspenseful music )
( sighing )
( eerie music )
( foreboding music )
- What 's the matter ?
St. Paul 's Church , September 8 , 1900 .
Joseph Patrick Carmichael .
It was there .
- It was there .
( ominous music )
- You have to show it to the police .
It 's the only piece of solid evidence we 've got .
- They didn 't see me dig it up .
They couldn 't find it .
Why should they believe it was there ?
- You can 't just ignore them .
- The police aren 't going to trouble themselves
with a 70 year old case .
- Still , it 's an unsolved murder .
- Whatever is to be done has to be done by me .
I 've gotta get to Carmichael .
- He won 't see you now .
- He 'll see me .
( horn honking )
( plane zooming )
Senator !
Hey , Mr. Carmichael !
- Hold up !
- Senator !
- Wait a minute now ! Wait a minute now !
- Senator , I 'm John Russell !
I 'm living in your house !
Senator , look !
I wanna talk to him !
Let me go !
Senator !
Look at this medal !
It 's a baptism medal .
It 's got your name on it .
It was buried with the body !
A little boy !
Senator , the police know about it !
( plane engines whooshing )
- Who was that ? Some kind of crackpot ?
- I have no idea .
Nevermind , come on .
( whooshing )
Dale ?
I want you to radio back to police headquarters ,
Captain DeWitt .
Ask him to call me in Spokane .
This number .
- Yes sir .
( ominous music )
( dramatic music )
( deep banging )
( suspenseful music )
( doors banging )
- You goddamn son-of-a-bitch !
What is it you want ?
What do you want from me ? !
I 've done everything I can do !
There 's nothing more to do .
( birds chirping )
( knocking )
- Mr. Russell ?
- Yes ?
- My name is DeWitt , Captain DeWitt .
- Oh yes .
- I 'd like to talk to you , if I may ?
- All right , come in .
- Quite a house .
- Yes .
- You 're a musician , a composer .
Is that right , Mr. Russell ?
- Yes .
- You teaching a course of the faculty of music
out at the university ?
- That 's right .
Is this where you held your seance ?
- What was it you wanted to talk to me about ?
- You were out at Boeing Airfield this morning , Mr. Russell .
They tell me you caused quite a scene .
Screaming and yelling , acting like a lunatic .
Sergeant Durban tells me you were up to some strange things
last night too .
Seems you dug up some bones under a lady 's house .
That some ghostly voice told you were there .
Is that correct ?
Only Sergeant Durban said you told him
you had no idea who those bones were , no idea at all .
Now it seems a little odd , then , don 't you think ,
that you 'd go charging across that airfield this morning ,
making crazy accusations against Senator Carmichael .
- I made no accusations .
- Senator Carmichael , who has served this state
for 36 years
and who is not about to give in to
any dirty , little blackmail schemes .
- Blackmail ? - [ Dewitt ] You heard me .
- What 're you talking about ?
- I understand you lost your wife and daughter
a little while ago .
Maybe it shook you up .
Maybe too much .
Maybe you need help .
- I 'd like you to leave now .
- We can see that you get it .
Do you understand what I 'm saying ?
- Out ! Now !
- Listen to me , Russell ,
you 've got something of the Senator 's .
He wants it back .
It 's a little gold medal , a family heirloom .
He lost it .
He thinks you 've got it .
( knocking )
- I don 't know what you 're talking about .
- I 'm sorry to barge in on you like this
but I am so damn mad !
This morn ...
- This is Captain DeWitt .
He 's with the police .
- You 're Miss Norman ?
- Yes .
- I take it now or I come back in an hour
with a warrant and a crew and we tear this place apart .
- Tear this place apart ?
What 's going on here ?
- I 'll be here .
- Suit yourself .
- What was that all about ?
- Senator Carmichael thinks he 's being blackmailed .
- They 've canceled your lease .
They 've forced me to resign from the Society .
No explanation , no reason , nothing .
Just get out .
I have an appointment with the head
of the board of directors .
I 'll see what I can find out .
I 'll call you and let you know .
( ominous music )
( eerie music )
( clock ticking )
( glass shattering )
( menacing music )
( phone ringing )
- Yes ?
Yes , Claire .
- I was driving by and I recognized the car .
I don 't know how it happened .
I don 't know how it could have happened .
There are no other cars . There 's nothing .
And it 's upside down in the middle of the road .
It 's that man , that policeman , that was just at your house !
DeWitt , he 's dead !
( plane whooshing )
( helicopter buzzing )
- Carmichael .
Any messages ?
Oh yes , Captain DeWitt .
What did he say ?
What ?
Yeah .
Oh my God .
- What ?
- Who ?
Russell ?
All right .
Let me have the number .
( ominous music )
( thunder rumbling )
- John Russell .
- The senator is expecting you .
( ominous music )
( eerie music )
- Still busy ?
- Yes .
( ominous music )
- Where are you going ?
- I 'll be back in a little while .
- Claire !
( ominous music )
- All right , just what the hell do you want ?
- You must have some idea ,
otherwise I wouldn 't have gotten past the door .
- Well I 'm a busy man , make it fast .
- The house on Chessman Park .
Your family lived there until 1906 .
( sighing )
It 's had a history of strange happenings .
There 's something in that house , a manifestation .
This afternoon , Captain DeWitt came to see me .
Presumably on your behalf .
So you must 've know what 's happened .
At least as must as DeWitt could tell you .
The disturbances , the seance ,
the bones found in the well .
I tried to talk to you at the airport .
I showed you this .
DeWitt said you lost it .
I found it in the grave where the child was buried .
There 's no logical explanation
for what I 'm going to say to you now .
The boy was badly crippled .
I believe he was killed in an attic room of that house .
I saw what happened .
I believe it was Richard Carmichael , your father ,
who murdered the boy , his natural son ,
Joseph Carmichael .
There was a substitution from the Sacred Heart Orphanage .
The boy was taken to Europe ,
cured miraculously
and returned to inherit an empire .
That changeling was you .
- So that 's your story .
- Whatever you wanna call it .
- How much ?
- My God .
- All right , how much do you want for
this farce that you 've concocted ?
- This isn 't blackmail .
- I 've been dealing with vermin like you for years .
You wait your chance , then you come in with a story - -
- The story terrifies you , doesn 't it ?
It 's the truth , it won 't be buried .
- Get out !
- None of this belongs to you .
- Get out of here with your filthy lies .
- It should 've gone to that dead child .
You suspected something was wrong all your life .
You 're not Joseph Carmichael .
You 're the beneficiary of the cruelest kind of murder .
Murder for profit !
- No !
My father was not a murderer !
Nobody in this world can say that !
My father was a great man .
He was a loving man
and for you to come in here and accuse him of ...
Of killing .
Damn you !
I will not allow you to slander his good name .
- These documents are on file with the city .
This is the tape of the seance .
There 's no copy .
Take it , I 've done what I had to do .
I 'm sorry .
- Russell .
If I find that you 've breathed one word of this ,
one word to anyone ,
you 'll wish that you 've never come into this world .
( dramatic music )
- What 's the yelling about ?
- Nothing .
Get out !
Leave me alone !
( ominous music )
( thunder rumbling )
( wind howling )
( door creaking )
- John ?
I tried to call .
( ominous music )
John ?
( booming )
- [ John ] This isn 't like me .
- John , where are you ?
( thunder rumbling )
( John mumbling )
John , what 're you doing ?
John ?
- [ John ] What do you want ? !
( eerie music )
( thunder rumbling )
Joseph 's coming .
( John yelling )
( menacing music )
( door creaking )
- John ?
Please .
I don 't wanna come up there .
- [ John ] Claire ?
- John ?
( eerie music )
( creaking )
John ?
( screaming )
( suspenseful music )
( growling )
( screaming )
Oh John !
I was calling you ! I was calling you !
( glass rattling )
( thunder rumbling )
You were here .
I kept calling you !
( gasping )
- You 're all right , calm down .
Just wait in the car for me .
- Oh no , you can 't go back in there !
No , please ! Please , no !
- Claire !
( sobbing )
I 'll be right back , don 't worry .
( suspenseful music )
Joseph , no !
( wind howling )
( suspenseful music )
( glass rattling )
( booming )
( wind howling )
( suspenseful music )
( fire rumbling )
( eerie music )
- [ Joseph ] Father !
Father !
( ominous music )
My medal !
( rattling )
Father ! Father !
Father !
My medal .
( menacing music )
( fire rumbling )
( wood creaking )
( rumbling )
( menacing music )
( deep pounding )
( glass rattling )
( banging )
- John !
John !
( fire rumbling )
( dramatic music )
( screaming )
( fire rumbling )
( dramatic music )
- [ Joseph ] My medal !
My medal ! My medal !
Father !
Help !
( water sloshing )
( boy gasping )
( rattling )
( deep pounding )
( water splashing )
( explosion rumbling )
( ominous music )
( police radio commotion )
( dramatic music )
( siren alarming )
( sirens alarming )
( dramatic music )
( wind howling )
( clicking )
( music box tune chiming )